<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://judgelord.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://judgelord.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://judgelord.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/PS272/syllabus-PS272-2020.html&#34;&gt;PS 272: Public Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/PS811/&#34;&gt;PS 811: Statistical Computing for Political Science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I study public policymaking, congressional oversight and representation, and environmental policy. My current work focuses on how civic engagement through public pressure campaigns affects agency rulemaking. I examine who participates in public pressure campaigns and why, whether they affect congressional oversight, and whether they affect policy. My work employs a range of quantitative and qualitative methods, with contributions mostly in the field of text analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;public-pressure-and-policymaking&#34;&gt;Public pressure and policymaking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current book project is about public pressure campaigns that target U.S. federal agency rulemaking, a technocratic policy process in which participation is usually limited to a few policy insiders. Occasionally, however, public pressure campaigns help make agency rules some of the most hotly contested policies of our time. I examine who organizes public pressure campaigns and why, whether these campaigns affect congressional oversight, and whether they affect policy. Answering these questions informs our understanding of bureaucratic politics as well as interest group lobbying, organizing, and mobilizing tactics. Most comments that federal agencies receive on their draft policies come from ordinary people who were inspired by a public pressure campaign. Yet, leading theories of bureaucratic policymaking neither explain nor account for these fitful bursts of civic engagement. This dissertation develops and tests theories about the roles of individuals, organizations, coalitions, and social movements in bureaucratic policymaking. I show that pressure campaigns build movements, attract policymakers&#39; attention, and systematically counter corporate power by generating information about public demands and the political environment in which policy is made. At the same time, I find that the impact of pressure campaigns is uneven and contingent on the capacity of interest groups to mobilize and of policymakers to process political information. I make four main contributions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I build on scholarship on social movements, interest group behavior, and lobbying to identify three reasons for lobbying organizations to mobilize ordinary people. Each logic suggests a different observable pattern of public engagement, and I analyze millions of public comments on thousands of agency rules to develop the first systematic measures of public engagement in bureaucratic policymaking. I find that &lt;a href=&#34;whymail&#34;&gt;most public comments are mobilized by public interest organizations&lt;/a&gt;, not by narrow private interests or astroturf campaigns. However, because campaigns require significant organizational capacity and resources, public comment campaigns are dominated by a few large policy advocacy organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, building on theories of political oversight, I theorize that mass engagement in bureaucratic policymaking may alert elected officials to political opportunities and risks, thus affecting oversight behaviors. I assess this argument by analyzing correspondence between members of Congress and agency officials on proposed rules with and without mass engagement. I find that public pressure campaigns are correlated with congressional attention and that &lt;a href=&#34;oversight&#34;&gt;coalitions with more congressional support are more likely to achieve their policy goals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, I integrate intuitions about outside lobbying and oversight into a broader theory of how public pressure campaigns may affect policy by producing potentially influential political information. I suggest four causal mechanisms by which lobbying may influence policymakers and expand leading formal models of interest group influence in bureaucratic policymaking to account for political information. I then test these models using a &lt;a href=&#34;iterative&#34;&gt;mix of hand-coding and computational text analysis methods&lt;/a&gt;. I find evidence of indirect effects but little evidence of direct effects of pressure campaigns on policy, especially for public interest campaigns. However, decisions to organize depend on anticipated lobbying success. Private interest groups only lobby when they expect to influence policy, whereas public interest groups also organize campaigns to build power. Thus, my results may understate the impact of public interest campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourth, I contribute to a growing literature on the effects of social movements through a case study of the environmental justice movement. I show that pressure campaigns are more than a lobbying tactic; they are also an institutionalized form of contentious politics over the distribution of governmental power. I examine the discursive effects of environmental justice claims both qualitatively and quantitatively, including the role of Native American activists and environmental groups in shaping federal policy. Though they frequently ignore environmental justice concerns, &lt;a href=&#34;ej&#34;&gt;agency officials are more likely to add language addressing environmental justice in their final rules when public comments and pressure campaigns raise environmental justice concerns&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a separate project on rulemaking, I built another novel dataset using internal rulemaking project status reports, offering the first systematic data on rulemaking activities before the publication of a Notice of Proposed Rulemaking (the starting point for all previous quantitative studies of timing, duration, and delay in rulemaking). These data allow us to study rulemaking across pre- and post-NPRM stages. Using multi-state duration models, we find that producing draft rules is a dynamic policy process and that the timing of NPRM publication is affected by many of the political variables known to affect the publication of final rules. This project is in collaboration with Susan Webb Yackee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I work to make data on agency rulemaking and interest group lobbying available to scholars. Cleaned datasets, including the Unified Agenda, Office of Information of Regulatory Affairs reports, and rules and comments posted to regulations.gov are available on my GitHub. Opportunities and challenges for research using these data and others are described in &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;regdata&#34;&gt;Data and Methods for Analyzing Special Interest Influence in Rulemaking&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; in &lt;em&gt;Interest Groups &amp;amp; Advocacy&lt;/em&gt; with Dan Carpenter, Brian Libgober, and Steve Rashin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;congressional-oversight-and-representation&#34;&gt;Congressional oversight and representation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To uncover the drivers of congressional oversight and representation, I am building a large new dataset on interactions between Members of Congress and other parts of the federal government. Through hundreds of Freedom of Information Act Requests, web scraping, and data wrangling, we have assembled data on half a million letters, emails, and phone calls from Members of Congress to federal agencies. These data yield new insights into legislator behavior. For example, we find that &lt;a href=&#34;correspondence&#34;&gt;as legislators gain institutional power and experience, they do more policy oversight and constituent service&lt;/a&gt;. We also find that &lt;a href=&#34;ferc&#34;&gt;legislators who receive campaign contributions from energy companies are more likely to advocate for those companies&lt;/a&gt;. This work is in collaboration with Eleanor Neff Powell and Justin Grimmer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another project on interbranch relations and oversight, I use text analysis to study the agenda-setting power of U.S. federal agency budget proposals and congressional appropriations sub-committee reports (see my PolMeth poster on modeling relationships among texts &lt;a href=&#34;budgets&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). I collect and clean a corpus of texts and develop computational methods to detect influence across political texts that enable novel studies of influence in policymaking. I find that changes in party control substantially affect the text of budget documents, suggesting that the policy effects of budget documents go far beyond the numbers they contain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;environmental-policy&#34;&gt;Environmental policy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to my dissertation&amp;rsquo;s substantive focus on environmental policy, I have two collaborative projects examining the role of private actors in global environmental governance through case studies of forestry policy. My article in &lt;em&gt;Organisation &amp;amp; The Environment&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;fsc-sfi&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Do Private Regulations Ratchet Up?&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt;) with Ben Cashore and Constance McDermott clarifies debates in the private governance literature by offering methods to measure regulatory stringency. Using these methods, we compare the forest management practices required by the activist-backed Forest Stewardship Council and industry-backed Sustainable Forestry Initiative. Overall, we find the activist-backed requirements to be increasingly more prescriptive. More importantly, we show how various studies have come to different conclusions by focusing on different dimensions of regulatory stringency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another project on the role of private actors in shaping policy with Irene Scher and Ben Cashore assesses the role of U.S. advocacy groups in shaping Canada&amp;rsquo;s forestry regulations. Tracing the history and policy process leading to the world&amp;rsquo;s largest conservation initiative, the Canadian Boreal Forest Agreement, we argue that while &amp;ldquo;Big Green&amp;rdquo; NGOs claimed credit, local First Nations groups had laid the necessary groundwork. This work was published as a peer-reviewed book chapter, &amp;ldquo;Non-domestic Sources of Canadian Boreal Forest Policy.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;working-papers&#34;&gt;Working papers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/talk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cvs</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discusses</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/discuss/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/discuss/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Templates</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/templates/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
