<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>https://judgelord.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://judgelord.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description></description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://judgelord.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Democratic ideals of public participation and equal voice in government extend beyond elections. Yet the role of the public in crafting policy agendas, drafting policy text, and overseeing implementation is complex. Policymaking processes include some people and ideas while excluding others in different ways at different stages. I study how organized groups and public pressure affect multiple stages of policymaking&amp;mdash;from how advocacy campaigns frame policy debates to how congressional oversight and judicial review shape implementation. I am especially interested in climate and environmental justice campaigns. I also lead large collaborative projects examining legislator behavior, lobbying, and private environmental governance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My work employs a range of quantitative and qualitative methods, with particular contributions in the field of text analysis. By building large open-source datasets and methods to analyze large volumes of political texts, I aim to expand the aspects of policymaking that are open to systematic study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;public-pressure-and-policymaking&#34;&gt;Public pressure and policymaking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My book project, &lt;em&gt;Public Pressure&lt;/em&gt;, shows how civic engagement through public pressure campaigns affects policymaking, with special attention to climate and environmental justice campaigns. Its five parts address (1) why groups mobilize public pressure, (2) how public pressure affects congressional oversight, (3) how it influences policy, (4) how it reframes policy debates, and (5) how it affects judicial review. Answering these questions clarifies the role of interest group lobbying, organizing, and mobilizing in policymaking. I show that some groups enjoy advantages in policymaking based on wealth, access, and expertise. And yet, I also show that disadvantaged groups are not powerless; movements and advocacy campaigns can reframe policy debates and systematically counter business influence in politics&amp;mdash;even in technocratic processes like agency rulemaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With 90 percent of U.S. law now made by federal agencies through rulemaking, understanding the politics of bureaucratic policymaking is critical to understanding our democracy. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Agency rulemaking is a technocratic policy process in which participation is usually limited to a few policy insiders. Occasionally, however, public pressure campaigns make agency rules some of the most hotly contested policies of our time. Yet, leading theories of bureaucratic policymaking neither explain nor account for these fitful bursts of civic engagement. To remedy this, I develop and test theories about the roles of individuals, elected officials, organizations, and coalitions in bureaucratic policymaking. I show that pressure campaigns build movements, attract policymakers&amp;rsquo; attention, and systematically counter corporate power. At the same time, I find that the impact of pressure campaigns is contingent on the capacity of interest groups to mobilize and of policymakers to process political information. Policy moves when high-capacity groups target receptive policymakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I draw on theories about social movements and interest groups to explain why different organizations mobilize public pressure. I argue that pressure campaigns are a form of conflict expansion that advantages coalitions with broader public support, not the narrow private interests that typically dominate policymaking. I analyze millions of public comments on thousands of agency rules to develop the first systematic measures of public engagement in policymaking for 161 federal agencies. I find that &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/whymail/&#34;&gt;most public comments are mobilized by public interest coalitions&lt;/a&gt;. However, because expanding the scope of conflict requires organizational capacity, campaigns are dominated by large advocacy organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second, I advance a theory of political oversight, with mass engagement in bureaucratic policymaking alerting elected officials to political risks and opportunities. I test this theory by analyzing correspondence between members of Congress and agency officials on proposed rules with and proposed rules without mass engagement. I find that public pressure campaigns are correlated with congressional attention and that &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/oversight/&#34;&gt;coalitions with more active congressional support are more likely to achieve their policy goals&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, I integrate theories of outside lobbying and oversight into a broader theory of how public pressure may affect policy. I test causal mechanisms by which public pressure may influence policymakers. Using &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/iterative/&#34;&gt;an iterative mix of hand-coding and computational text analysis methods&lt;/a&gt;, I measure lobbying success&amp;mdash;the extent to which each group got their desired changes between the draft and final rule&amp;mdash;for over 40 million commenters. I find evidence that pressure campaigns indirectly affect policy by mobilizing political oversight. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourth, I contribute to the literature on the effects of political movements on policy through case studies of the climate and environmental justice movements. I find that &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/ej/&#34;&gt;when groups raise distributive justice concerns, rules more often change to address these concerns&lt;/a&gt;. I show how institutions affect responsiveness. For example, agencies with an office of environmental justice are more responsive to environmental justice concerns. The scale of mobilization also matters; when larger coalitions raise concerns, policy texts are more likely to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fifth, I show that &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/deference/&#34;&gt;rules targeted by pressure campaigns were less likely to be struck down by the Supreme Court&lt;/a&gt; than rules that received less public attention. This supports the theory that public attention to policy issues affects judicial decisions because Justices care about public perceptions of the Court.
The book concludes with policy recommendations for increasing the capacity of government institutions in all three branches to process, vet, and learn from what I call &amp;ldquo;political information&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;including public demands expressed through civic engagement and pressure campaigns. For example, because offices dedicated to issues like civil rights and environmental justice make agencies more responsive to groups raising distributive justice concerns, my work suggests that creating offices dedicated to social justice and public participation are impactful reforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;additional-projects-on-agency-rulemaking&#34;&gt;Additional projects on agency rulemaking&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to my book project, I have several large collaborative projects on agency rulemaking. In a recent article in &lt;em&gt;Interest Groups and Advocacy&lt;/em&gt;, my coauthors and I outline research agendas on bureaucratic policymaking that leverage &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/regdata/&#34;&gt;new methods and data on interest-group lobbying&lt;/a&gt;. One project leverages a massive new dataset on all organizations that lobbied on financial regulation following the Dodd-Frank Act. Adding to work on inequality in American politics, we show that wealthy organizations are much more likely to participate in and influence rulemaking. We then assess mechanisms to explain the relationship between wealth and influence, finding that &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/finreg/&#34;&gt;wealthier organizations are more influential because they engage in more sophisticated lobbying&lt;/a&gt;. This paper won the APSA 2021 Best Paper Award from the Public Administration section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another collaborative project leverages the first large-scale data on the agenda-setting politics that produce initial draft rules. These data allow us to study rulemaking across pre- and post-draft rule stages (prior quantitative studies only observe post-draft politics). We show that external shocks to bureaucratic policymaking, such as presidential transitions, have even larger effects on rules in the period between project initiation and draft publication (rules yet to be announced) than in the period between draft and final rule. &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;congressional-oversight-and-representation&#34;&gt;Congressional oversight and representation&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My second broad research agenda examines variation in how legislators represent constituents in various interactions with the bureaucracy&amp;mdash;from constituency service to policy oversight. Beyond my work on how pressure campaigns mobilize congressional oversight, my work on legislator behavior includes several coauthored articles, a collaborative book project, and an ongoing data collection effort. From the vantage point of detailed observation of legislator offices, our book project addresses how Congress is working, who is left behind, who is getting extra attention, and how to improve congressional representation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through hundreds of Freedom of Information Act requests and web scraping, my coauthors, research assistants, and I assembled and hand-coded over half a million letters, emails, and phone calls from members of Congress to federal agencies. These data allow new tests of theories of legislator behavior. In the first peer-reviewed publication from this project, we show that &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/ferc/&#34;&gt;legislators who receive more campaign donations from fossil fuel companies are more likely to intervene to support those companies&lt;/a&gt; in regulatory issues. Another paper, currently under review, shows that &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/correspondence/&#34;&gt;legislators prioritize policy work as they gain institutional power but still provide the same levels of constituency service&lt;/a&gt;. A third working paper shows that legislators provide constituency service to seniors and veterans in proportion to populations in their district, but &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/correp/&#34;&gt;low-income constituents do not receive proportional constituency service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;environmental-governance&#34;&gt;Environmental governance&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to my main book project&amp;rsquo;s substantive focus on environmental policy, I have several collaborative projects on environmental governance. Like governmental policymaking, private actors exercise governing authority with varying levels of public participation. In an article in &lt;em&gt;Organization &amp;amp; Environment&lt;/em&gt; my coauthors and I clarify debates in the private governance literature by offering &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/fsc-sfi/&#34;&gt;new methods to measure regulatory stringency&lt;/a&gt;. We show how various studies arrived at opposite conclusions by focusing on different dimensions of regulatory stringency. We then compare the forest management practices required by the activist-backed Forest Stewardship Council and industry-backed Sustainable Forestry Initiative using these new methods. We find that these competing private regulations ratcheted &amp;ldquo;up&amp;rdquo; but also diverged&amp;mdash;with the activist-backed requirements becoming increasingly more prescriptive while industry-backed requirements increased in less prescriptive ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another project on the role of private actors in shaping policy assesses the role of U.S. advocacy groups in shaping Canada&amp;rsquo;s forestry regulations. In a peer-reviewed book chapter, my coauthors and I trace the policy process leading to the world&amp;rsquo;s largest conservation initiative, the Canadian Boreal Forest Agreement. We argue that while &amp;ldquo;Big Green&amp;rdquo; NGOs claimed credit, local First Nations groups laid the necessary groundwork.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;future-research&#34;&gt;Future research&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My future research will focus on two themes arising from my current work: institutional capacity and policy feedback effects. First, major findings from several of my current projects point to the capacity of government institutions to translate public demands into policy as an understudied linchpin of democracy. For example, I am investigating why some agencies appear to have more capacity to respond to calls to address environmental justice and climate change than others. This will include audit-style field experiments randomizing the targets and content of public comments to assess how different institutions respond to different types of information (e.g., different justifications for addressing climate or environmental justice). This project will also explore how congressional offices and courts could develop the capacity to more routinely incorporate public input into decisions. My aim is to improve the infrastructure of democratic responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second nascent project follows from my work on how groups organize around opportunities for public participation. Following the causal chain, I am exploring how opportunities to participate in policymaking affect group formation, organization, and mobilization. Whereas most policy feedback studies trace the effects of legislation on voters, my project examines how procedural policy tools like notice and comment rulemaking mobilize and demobilize organized groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;methods&#34;&gt;Methods&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The methods I developed for integrating human coding of texts with computational text analysis increase the inferential power of hand coding by several orders of magnitude. Computational text analysis tools can strategically select texts for human coders, including texts that represent larger samples and outlier texts of high inferential value. Preprocessing documents can speed hand-coding by extracting key features like named entities. For example, my R package &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/legislators/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;legislators&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; helps users extract U.S. legislator names in messy text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I show that hand-coding and text analysis tools are each more powerful when combined in an interactive workflow. Using this &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/iterative/&#34;&gt;iterative mix of hand-coding and computational text analysis methods&lt;/a&gt;, a hand-coded sample of 10,894 hand-coded comments yields equally valid inferences for over 40 million comments regarding the extent to which policy changed in the direction they sought. I thus measure lobbying success&amp;mdash;the extent to which each group got their desired changes between the draft and final policy&amp;mdash;for millions of people and thousands of organizations. This large sample enables new analyses of the relationships between lobbying coalitions, social movements, and policy change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to making text analysis tools more accessible, my R package &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/netlit/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;netlit&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and coauthored work with an R&amp;amp;R at &lt;em&gt;Political Analysis&lt;/em&gt; make powerful network analysis tools more accessible for scholars conducting literature reviews. Understanding the gaps and connections across existing theories and findings is a perennial challenge in scientific research. Systematically reviewing scholarship is especially challenging for researchers who may lack domain expertise, including junior scholars or those exploring new substantive territory. Conversely, senior scholars may rely on longstanding assumptions and social networks that exclude new research. In both cases, ad hoc literature reviews hinder the accumulation of knowledge. Scholars are rarely systematic in selecting relevant prior work or then identifying patterns across their sample. To encourage systematic, replicable, and transparent methods for assessing literature, we propose an accessible &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/netlit/&#34;&gt;network-based framework for reviewing scholarship&lt;/a&gt;. In our method, we consider a literature as a network of recurring concepts (nodes) and theorized relationships among them (edges). Network statistics and visualization allow researchers to see patterns and offer reproducible characterizations of assertions about the major themes in the existing literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;working-papers&#34;&gt;Working papers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/cv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml&#34; lang=&#34;en&#34; xml:lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;&lt;head&gt;

&lt;meta charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;
&lt;meta name=&#34;generator&#34; content=&#34;quarto-1.8.26&#34;&gt;

&lt;meta name=&#34;viewport&#34; content=&#34;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0, user-scalable=yes&#34;&gt;

&lt;meta name=&#34;author&#34; content=&#34;Devin Judge-Lord&#34;&gt;
&lt;meta name=&#34;dcterms.date&#34; content=&#34;2026-01-29&#34;&gt;

&lt;title&gt;index&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;style&gt;
code{white-space: pre-wrap;}
span.smallcaps{font-variant: small-caps;}
div.columns{display: flex; gap: min(4vw, 1.5em);}
div.column{flex: auto; overflow-x: auto;}
div.hanging-indent{margin-left: 1.5em; text-indent: -1.5em;}
ul.task-list{list-style: none;}
ul.task-list li input[type=&#34;checkbox&#34;] {
  width: 0.8em;
  margin: 0 0.8em 0.2em -1em; /* quarto-specific, see https://github.com/quarto-dev/quarto-cli/issues/4556 */ 
  vertical-align: middle;
}
&lt;/style&gt;


&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/libs/clipboard/clipboard.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/libs/quarto-html/quarto.js&#34; type=&#34;module&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/libs/quarto-html/tabsets/tabsets.js&#34; type=&#34;module&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/libs/quarto-html/axe/axe-check.js&#34; type=&#34;module&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/libs/quarto-html/popper.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/libs/quarto-html/tippy.umd.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/libs/quarto-html/anchor.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;index_files/libs/quarto-html/tippy.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34;&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;index_files/libs/quarto-html/quarto-syntax-highlighting-587c61ba64f3a5504c4d52d930310e48.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; id=&#34;quarto-text-highlighting-styles&#34;&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;index_files/libs/bootstrap/bootstrap.min.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;index_files/libs/bootstrap/bootstrap-icons.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34;&gt;
&lt;link href=&#34;index_files/libs/bootstrap/bootstrap-772c80b1430f8ee4cbac18a9e3589be2.min.css&#34; rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; append-hash=&#34;true&#34; id=&#34;quarto-bootstrap&#34; data-mode=&#34;light&#34;&gt;


&lt;/head&gt;

&lt;body class=&#34;quarto-light&#34;&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;quarto-content&#34; class=&#34;page-columns page-rows-contents page-layout-article&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;quarto-margin-sidebar&#34; class=&#34;sidebar margin-sidebar&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quarto-alternate-formats&#34;&gt;&lt;h2&gt;Other Formats&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;index.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;bi bi-file-pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;main class=&#34;content&#34; id=&#34;quarto-document-content&#34;&gt;

&lt;header id=&#34;title-block-header&#34; class=&#34;quarto-title-block default&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quarto-title&#34;&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;quarto-title-meta&#34;&gt;

    
    &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;quarto-title-meta-heading&#34;&gt;Published&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;quarto-title-meta-contents&#34;&gt;
      &lt;p class=&#34;date&#34;&gt;January 29, 2026&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  


&lt;/header&gt;


&lt;div class=&#34;center&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant Professor, University of Michigan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3215 Weill Hall, 735 S State St, Ann Arbor, MI 48109&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;bi bi-envelope&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:judgelor@umich.edu&#34;&gt;judgelor@umich.edu&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;i class=&#34;bi bi-globe&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/&#34;&gt;judgelord.github.io&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;em&gt;Updated&lt;/em&gt; Jan.&amp;nbsp;29, 2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;academic-positions&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;ACADEMIC POSITIONS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Michigan, Ford School of Public Policy, Assistant Professor (2023-present)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michigan Institute for Data and AI in Society (MIDAS) Faculty Affiliate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harvard University, Department of Government, Postdoctoral Fellow (2021-2023)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Harvard Center for the Environment (HUCE)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Center for American Political Studies (CAPS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;education&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;EDUCATION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Wisconsin–Madison, M.A.&amp;nbsp;(2017) and Ph.D.&amp;nbsp;(2021) in Political Science&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dissertation: &lt;em&gt;Public Pressure Campaigns and Bureaucratic Policymaking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Committee: Susan Webb Yackee (Chair), Eleanor Powell, Alex Tahk, David Weimer, Miriam Seifter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yale University, M.E.Sc. in Environmental Policy and Law (2013) &lt;!--Master of Environmental Science  (2013)--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thesis: &lt;em&gt;Mechanisms of Policy Feedback in U.S. Farm and Forest Policy: Interactions Among Property Rights, Regulation, and Public Investments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reed College, B.A. in Political Science (2009)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;peer-reviewed-publications&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;hanging-indent&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;6.&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/correspondence/&#34;&gt;“The Effects of Shifting Priorities and Capacity on Policy Work and Constituency Service: Evidence from a Census of Legislator Requests to U.S. Federal Agencies” with Justin Grimmer and Eleanor Powell. &lt;em&gt;American Journal of Political Science&lt;/em&gt; (Forthcoming)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replication Data: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7910/DVN/LWOCWO&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.7910/DVN/LWOCWO&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;5.&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1017/pan.2023.4&#34;&gt;“Mapping Literature with Networks: An Application to Redistricting” with Adeline Lo, Kyler Hudson, Kenneth R. Mayer. &lt;em&gt;Political Analysis&lt;/em&gt; (2023)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;4.&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/ferc/&#34;&gt;“Campaign Contributions and Bureaucratic Oversight: A Case Study of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission” with Eleanor Powell and Justin Grimmer in &lt;em&gt;Accountability Reconsidered: Voters, Interests, and Information in U.S. Policymaking&lt;/em&gt;, ed.&amp;nbsp;Charles M. Cameron, Brandice Canes-Wrone, Sanford C. Gordon, Gregory A. Huber, Cambridge University Press (2022)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;3.&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1057/s41309-020-00094-w&#34;&gt;“Data and Methods for Analyzing Interest Group Influence in Rulemaking” with Daniel Carpenter, Brian Libgober, Steven Rashin. &lt;em&gt;Interest Groups &amp;amp; Advocacy&lt;/em&gt; 9:425–435 (2020)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;2.&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/full/10.1177/1086026619858874&#34;&gt;“Do Private Regulations Ratchet Up? How to Distinguish Types of Regulatory Stringency and Patterns of Change” with Benjamin Cashore and Constance McDermott in &lt;em&gt;Organization &amp;amp; Environment&lt;/em&gt; 33:1 96–125 (2020)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;1.&lt;/code&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/boreal&#34;&gt;“Non-domestic Sources of Canadian Boreal Forest Policy: Integrating Theories of Internationalization and Pathways of Policy Change” with Irene Scher and Benjamin Cashore in &lt;em&gt;Forests Under Pressure: Local Responses to Global Issues&lt;/em&gt; (2015)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;working-papers&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;WORKING PAPERS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;!--
&#34;The Two Faces of Bureaucratic Policymaking: Before and after draft rules go public&#34; with Susan Yackee
--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;“Words and Deeds: Evaluating How Legislators’ Constituent-Facing Communication about Federal Agencies Compares to Their Behind-the-Scenes Work with Federal Agencies” with Jessie Munson, Rochelle Snyder, Eleanor Neff Powell&lt;/a&gt; (MPSA 2025, under review)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/finreg/&#34;&gt;“Inequality in Administrative Democracy: Methods and Evidence from Financial Rulemaking” with Steven Rashin, Brian Libgober, Jacob Waggoner, Angelo Dagonel, Christopher T. Kenny, Susan Webb Yackee, and Daniel Carpenter&lt;/a&gt; (APSA 2021, submitted)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Herbert Kaufman Award for best paper in Public Administration presented at APSA 2022&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/racialization/mpsa-presentation.html&#34;&gt;“Racialization and Perceived Institutional Ideology” with Karla Magana&lt;/a&gt; (MPSA 2025)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/ej/APSA2024.html&#34;&gt;“Adoption and Cooption of the Environmental Justice Issue Frame”&lt;/a&gt; (APSA 2024)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/iterative&#34;&gt;“Iterative Hand-Coding and Computational Text Analysis”&lt;/a&gt; (PolMeth 2022) &lt;!--: Application to Assessing the Effects of Public Pressure on Policy--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/ej/&#34;&gt;“Making Policy About Distributive Justice: The Environmental Justice Movement’s Impact on Agency Rulemaking”&lt;/a&gt; (APSA 2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/cj/&#34;&gt;“Making Policy About Climate Change: The Climate Movement’s Impact on Agency Rulemaking”&lt;/a&gt; (Climate Pipeline Conference 2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/correp/&#34;&gt;“Who Gets Constituent Service?” with Rochelle Snyder, Justin Grimmer, and Eleanor Powell&lt;/a&gt; (APSA 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/whymail/&#34;&gt;“Why Do Agencies (Sometimes) Get So Much Mail? Lobbying Coalitions, Mass Comments, and Political Information in Bureaucratic Policymaking”&lt;/a&gt; (SPSA 2019)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/budgets&#34;&gt;“Measuring Change and Influence in Budget Texts”&lt;/a&gt; (PolMeth 2017, APSA 2017)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/defrence/&#34;&gt;“Why Courts Defer to Administrative Agency Judgement”&lt;/a&gt; (MPSA 2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- &#34;U.S. Domestic Politics of Climate Engineering&#34; (AESS 2016)
---&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Revisiting the Democratic Case for Carbon and Environmental Offset Markets” (Governance, Environment, and Markets Workshop at Yale University, 2013)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--&#34;Mechanisms of Policy Feedback: Interactions Among Regulations and Public Investments in U.S. Farm and Forest Politics&#34; (MESc Thesis, Yale University 2013)--&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;other-publications&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;OTHER PUBLICATIONS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Institutional Changes Needed to Implement Ecosystem-based Plans” with John Robert Cochran, &lt;em&gt;Oregon Planners Journal&lt;/em&gt; 28(1):7 (2011)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;software&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;SOFTWARE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/regulationsdotgov/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;regulationsdotgov&lt;/code&gt;: A package to build datasets of US federal policy documents and their metadata in R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/netlit/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;netlit&lt;/code&gt;: A package to aid literature reviews with network analysis in R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/legislators/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;legislators&lt;/code&gt;: A package to find legislator names in messy text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/congressionalrecord/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;congressionalrecord&lt;/code&gt;: A package to scrape, parse, and analyze the Congressional Record&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/regextable&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;regextable&lt;/code&gt;: Faster, easier, string matching for data science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;teaching&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;TEACHING&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Michigan, Assistant Professor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Protest, Social Movements, Art, and Policy Change (Graduate, 2026)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Climate Change and Democracy (Undergraduate, 2024, 2025)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Politics for the Anthropocene (Undergraduate, 2024, 2025)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Politics of Public Policy (Graduate, 2023, 2024, 2025)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Independent Study - Political Science (Undergraduate, 2024-2026)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Wisconsin–Madison, Lecturer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public Policy (Undergraduate, 2019, 2020)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Statistical Computing in Political Science (Graduate, 2019)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Wisconsin–Madison, Teaching Assistant/Grader&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Public Policy (Undergraduate, 2016, 2017, 2018)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Policing in the United States (Undergraduate, 2015)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yale University, Teaching Fellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Politics and Practice of Environmental Policy (Graduate, 2012)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Economics of Ecosystems and Biodiversity (Graduate, 2011)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;selected-awards&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;SELECTED AWARDS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching Honor Roll, University of Michigan (2024, 2025, 2026)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Paper in Public Administration, American Political Science Association conference: &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/finreg/&#34;&gt;“Inequality in Administrative Democracy”&lt;/a&gt; (2022)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Dissertation in American Politics, University of Wisconsin–Madison (2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Levin Center Congressional Oversight Fellow (2021-2022)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National Science Foundation (NSF) Doctoral Dissertation Research Improvement Grant (2020) &lt;!--, awarded by the American Political Science Association (APSA) --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exceptional Mentorship Award, Undergraduate Research Scholars Program, UW–Madison (2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summer Research Initiative Research Award, UW–Madison (2018, 2019, 2020, 2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Follette Fellowship, University of Wisconsin La Follette School of Public Affairs (2016)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finalist, Best Student Paper, Association of Environmental Studies and Sciences (2015)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Master’s Thesis Research Award (runner-up), selected by faculty among all social and natural science Masters Theses (Yale School of the Environment, 2013)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best Student Paper Award, Association for Environmental Studies and Sciences (2012)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carpenter-Sperry Research Award (2012)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jubitz Family Foundation Research Fellowship (2012)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;H. Stuart Harrison Scholarship to attend Yale University (2011–2013)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morton O’Stafford Scholarship to attend Reed College (2006–2009)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pell Grant (2005-2009)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;public-policy-and-research-positions&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;PUBLIC POLICY AND RESEARCH POSITIONS&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visiting Scholar, New York University, Department of Politics (2021-2022)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affiliated Researcher, Yale Governance, Environment, and Markets (GEM) Initiative (2013–2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Consultant, Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (2013–2014)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Compared forestry laws across countries with quantitative and qualitative text analysis&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wrote policy-focused portions of the State of the World’s Forests Report&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulatory Affairs Specialist, Washington County, Oregon (2010–2011)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convened state and federal agency staff to draft Oregon Department of Environmental Quality Guidance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drafted text for an Oregon State Senate bill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Conducted a feasibility analysis that led to $10 million in private conservation investment, $1 million in public investment, and praise for the project in a speech by President Barack Obama&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ducey Fellow for Public Policy, Willamette Partnership (2009)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research Intern, Center for Transboundary Cooperation, Saint-Petersburg State University, Russia (2008)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;section id=&#34;service&#34; class=&#34;level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;SERVICE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PhD Program Committee, Ford School of Public Policy (2024-2026)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Water@Michigan Faculty Steering Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. State Department/Weiser Diplomacy Center Diplomacy Lab, with the Department of the Treasury. (2024-2025)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Masters Program Committee, Ford School of Public Policy (2023-2024)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewer: &lt;em&gt;American Political Science Review&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Public Administration Research and Theory&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Politics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Public Policy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Perspectives on Politics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Regulation &amp;amp; Governance&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Current Opinion in Sustainability&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Journal of Forest Policy and Economics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social Media Editor (2017-2024), American Political Science Association section on Science, Technology, and Environmental Politics (APSA STEP)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Program Committee (2014–2016), Nominations Committee (Elected, 2016-2022), Association of Environmental Studies and Sciences (AESS)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
PhD Advisor

- Branden Bohrnsen
--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dissertation Committees&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Karla Magana (University of Michigan, Political Science and Public Policy)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maya Khuzam (University of Michigan, Political Science)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentor, Undergraduate Research Opportunity Program (UROP), University of Michigan (2023-present)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentees: Antonio Isho, Lily Bourgeois, Jesse Duby, Niyatee Jain, Grace Lee, Scotten Maderal, Arvin Pandiyan, Ava Malin, Farah Kavarana, Genevieve Fettig, Meiting Xu, Mia Alderman, Samantha Lay, Shakuntala Balusu, Scotten Maderal, Summit Shaw, Jessica Rehberg, Zayn Merrick, Emma Weiss, Aya Soweidan, Naya Ramaswami, Brody Amthor, Stephanie Bouserhal, Justin Chen, Lyndon Dibble, Aamir Kapasi, Madison Knowlton, Ashanti Mirelez, Kaito Patterson, Olivia Savord, Audrey Stocker, Gia Verma, Evan Weinraub, Anna Childs, Shirlyn Dong, Isabella Gentry, Steven Kang, Anna Kendzior, Ryan Rincones, Aaron Zhao, Kaito Patterson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;!-- Other Lab Members 
Karla Magana &lt;kmagana@umich.edu&gt;,
Gavriella Solomon &lt;gavriell@umich.edu&gt;,
Emily Laffey &lt;emlaffey@umich.edu&gt;,
Amant Grewal
Luke Dillingham ,
Deven Parikh
Julian 
Saman de Silva
Maya Khuzam
Will Cooper
--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervisor, Honors Thesis (University of Michigan)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jessica Rehberg (2025-2026)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervisor, Directed Study (University of Michigan)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gavriella Solomon, Emily Laffey (2024-2025)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-supervisor, Undergraduate Thesis (Harvard College)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robin Greene (2023-2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentor, Harvard University Center for the Environment (HUCE) Undergraduate Research Scholars Program (2022-2023)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentees: Davit Antonyan, Robin Greene, Tomoki Matsuno&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentor, Undergraduate Research Scholars Program, UW–Madison (2015-2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentees: Kendl Kobbervig, Kyra Fox, Mikayla Sandin, Daniel Nesslein, Hope Karnopp, Julia Derzay, Samiha Bhushan, Max Linse, Hailey Patel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mentor, Sophomore Research Fellows Program, UW–Madison (2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentee: Samiha Bhushan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supervisor, Honors Theses and Directed Studies, UW–Madison (2020-2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students: Maggie Nead, Fatima Ali, Samiha Bhushan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diversity and Inclusion Committee, UW–Madison Department of Political Science (2019-2021)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading Room Committee, UW–Madison Department of Political Science (2016-2019)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graduate School Representative, Associated Students of Madison Student Council (2016-2017)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vice-Chair (2012–2013), Workshops Chair (2011–2012), New Directions in Environmental Law conference at Yale Law School&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President, Yale Environmental Law Association Student Interest Group (2012–2013)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--
# INVITED TALKS

Yale Conference on Politics and Law in the Administrative State - &#34;Agencies and Stakeholders&#34; (2025)

University of Mississippi &#34;The Environmental Justice Movement&#39;s Impact on Technocratic Policymaking&#34; (2021)


# CERTIFICATIONS

Inclusive Teaching (4-day workshop, University of Wisconsin--Madison, 2020)

Teaching in the Social Sciences Certificate (Yale University, 2012)

&lt;!--River Restoration Professional Certificate (Portland State University, 2011)--&gt;
&lt;!--
# LANGUAGES

English (native), Spanish (conversational), Russian (basic), R, Python,  Stata, SQL, SPSS, Mathematica, Markdown, \LaTeX, HTML

# SELECTED COURSEWORK IN LAW

*Yale Law School*: Administrative Law; Energy Law; Property Law; Environmental Law; Land Use Law; Property, Social Justice, and the Environment

# SELECTED COURSEWORK BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

*Yale School of Management*: Corporate Environmental Management and Strategy


&lt;!--
# REFRENCES 

Susan Webb Yackee  
Director, La Follette School of Public Affairs  
Professor of Public Affairs and Political Science  
University of Wisconsin--Madison  
yackee@wisc.edu  
(608) 886-5215  


Eleanor Neff Powell  
Booth Fowler Associate Professor of Political Science  
University of Wisconsin--Madison  
eleanor.powell@wisc.edu  
(857) 991-9536  


&lt;!--
# SELECTED GRADUATE COURSEWORK

*Yale School of Forestry and Environmental Studies*: Political Economy (an independent study structured around the Political Economy Workshop in the Department of Political Science); Research and Writing in the Social Sciences; Corporate Environmental Strategy and Management; International Environmental Policy &amp; Governance

*Yale University, Department of Political Science*: Qualitative Field Research; The People

*University of Wisconsin--Madison, Department of Political Science*: Economic Inequality in Modern Political Thought; Race and Politics in the U.S.; Empirical Methods of Political Inquiry, Statistics in Political Science, Macro-theories of American Politics; The Legislative Process: Classics in American Politics; Maximum Likelihood Estimation; Game Theory &amp; Political Analysis; Statistical Computing; Statistical Inference; Experimental Methods; Bayesian Statistics



Project Assistant, University of Wisconsin--Madison (2015-Present)




---

PRESENTATIONS

American Political Science Association (2017, 2018)

Midwest Political Science Association (2016, 2020)

Association of Environmental Studies and Sciences Annual Conference (2012, 2018, 2019, 2020)

New Directions in Environmental Law Conference, Yale Law School (2012, 2013)

What if Plans Were the Law? with Professor Christopher Serkin. New Directions in Environmental Law Conference.
New Haven, CT. Mar. 2, 2013
Politics in Market Design: Stakeholder participation in U.S. water quality trading programs. Association of Environmental
Studies and Sciences 2012 Annual Conference. Santa Clara, CA. Jul. 21, 2012.
Old Laws, New Problems: Evolving strategies for water quality with Professor Ann Powers and Attorney Tom Lindley,
New Directions in Environmental Law conference. New Haven, CT. Feb. 25, 2012.
Ecosystem Markets 101 with Tracy Stanton and How Do Ecosystem Services Stack Up? panel presentation with Professor
Richard Woodward and Jimmy Duakas, moderated by Lydia Olander. The American Forest Foundation and World
Resources Institute&#39;s 4th annual Ecosystem Markets Conference. Madison, WI. Jun. 29, 2011.
Standards of Ecosystem Credit Accounting (and points of negotiation). California Roundtable on Agriculture and the
Environment. San Francisco, CA. Nov. 1, 2010.
Building Unique Local Markets With Shared Regional Infrastructure. Northwest Environmental Forum. University of
Washington, Seattle. Oct. 18, 2010.
Counting on the Environment: Salmonid, Wetland, and Prairie Habitat metrics. The American Forest Foundation and
World Resources Institute&#39;s 3rd Annual Environmental Markets Conference. Raleigh, NC. Jul. 22, 2010.

Travel Grant (Yale University 2011, 2012)






SKILLS AND LANGUAGES
R; Python; SPSS; Stata; Mathematica; basic ArcGIS; NVivo; Atlas.TI
Conversational Russian; basic Spanish


Discussant, Midwest Political Science Association (MPSA) annual conference (2015, 2016)

- Thesis: _Mechanisms of Policy Feedback: Interactions among Regulations and Public Investments_
Mechanisms of Policy Feedback: Interactions among Regulations and Public Investments in U.S. Farm and Forest Politics

- Thesis: _Mechanisms of Policy Feedback: Interactions among Regulations and Public Investments_

Research Assistant, Governance, Environment, and Markets (GEM) Initiative
• Analyzed methods employed in 220 journal articles


• Developed regulatory compliance strategies, convening state and federal agencies to secure a memorandum of understanding
on Clean Water Act compliance (now Oregon Department of Environmental Quality Guidance)
• Drafted legal language for an Oregon State Senate bill
• Conducted a feasibility analysis that led to \$10 million in private investment, $1 million
in public investment, and praise for the project in a speech by President Barack Obama



# REFERENCES

Daniel Carpenter    
Allie S. Freed Professor of Government  
Harvard University  
dcarpenter@gov.harvard.edu
 
Susan Webb Yackee  
Director, Robert M. La Follette School of Public Affairs  
Professor of Public Affairs  
University of Wisconsin--Madison  
yackee@wisc.edu

Eleanor Powell  
Booth Fowler Associate Professor of Political Science  
University of Wisconsin--Madison  
eleanor.powell@wisc.edu

David Weimer  
Edwin E. Witte Professor of Political Economy  
Robert M. La Follette School of Public Affairs  
University of Wisconsin--Madison  
weimer@lafollette.wisc.edu

Benjamin Cashore  
Li Ka Shing Professor in Public Management  
Director, Institute for Environment and Sustainability  
Lee Kuan Yew School of Public Policy  
sppbwc@nus.edu.sg
--&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;/main&gt;
&lt;!-- /main column --&gt;
&lt;script id=&#34;quarto-html-after-body&#34; type=&#34;application/javascript&#34;&gt;
  window.document.addEventListener(&#34;DOMContentLoaded&#34;, function (event) {
    const icon = &#34;&#34;;
    const anchorJS = new window.AnchorJS();
    anchorJS.options = {
      placement: &#39;right&#39;,
      icon: icon
    };
    anchorJS.add(&#39;.anchored&#39;);
    const isCodeAnnotation = (el) =&gt; {
      for (const clz of el.classList) {
        if (clz.startsWith(&#39;code-annotation-&#39;)) {                     
          return true;
        }
      }
      return false;
    }
    const onCopySuccess = function(e) {
      // button target
      const button = e.trigger;
      // don&#39;t keep focus
      button.blur();
      // flash &#34;checked&#34;
      button.classList.add(&#39;code-copy-button-checked&#39;);
      var currentTitle = button.getAttribute(&#34;title&#34;);
      button.setAttribute(&#34;title&#34;, &#34;Copied!&#34;);
      let tooltip;
      if (window.bootstrap) {
        button.setAttribute(&#34;data-bs-toggle&#34;, &#34;tooltip&#34;);
        button.setAttribute(&#34;data-bs-placement&#34;, &#34;left&#34;);
        button.setAttribute(&#34;data-bs-title&#34;, &#34;Copied!&#34;);
        tooltip = new bootstrap.Tooltip(button, 
          { trigger: &#34;manual&#34;, 
            customClass: &#34;code-copy-button-tooltip&#34;,
            offset: [0, -8]});
        tooltip.show();    
      }
      setTimeout(function() {
        if (tooltip) {
          tooltip.hide();
          button.removeAttribute(&#34;data-bs-title&#34;);
          button.removeAttribute(&#34;data-bs-toggle&#34;);
          button.removeAttribute(&#34;data-bs-placement&#34;);
        }
        button.setAttribute(&#34;title&#34;, currentTitle);
        button.classList.remove(&#39;code-copy-button-checked&#39;);
      }, 1000);
      // clear code selection
      e.clearSelection();
    }
    const getTextToCopy = function(trigger) {
      const outerScaffold = trigger.parentElement.cloneNode(true);
      const codeEl = outerScaffold.querySelector(&#39;code&#39;);
      for (const childEl of codeEl.children) {
        if (isCodeAnnotation(childEl)) {
          childEl.remove();
        }
      }
      return codeEl.innerText;
    }
    const clipboard = new window.ClipboardJS(&#39;.code-copy-button:not([data-in-quarto-modal])&#39;, {
      text: getTextToCopy
    });
    clipboard.on(&#39;success&#39;, onCopySuccess);
    if (window.document.getElementById(&#39;quarto-embedded-source-code-modal&#39;)) {
      const clipboardModal = new window.ClipboardJS(&#39;.code-copy-button[data-in-quarto-modal]&#39;, {
        text: getTextToCopy,
        container: window.document.getElementById(&#39;quarto-embedded-source-code-modal&#39;)
      });
      clipboardModal.on(&#39;success&#39;, onCopySuccess);
    }
      var localhostRegex = new RegExp(/^(?:http|https):\/\/localhost\:?[0-9]*\//);
      var mailtoRegex = new RegExp(/^mailto:/);
        var filterRegex = new RegExp(&#39;/&#39; + window.location.host + &#39;/&#39;);
      var isInternal = (href) =&gt; {
          return filterRegex.test(href) || localhostRegex.test(href) || mailtoRegex.test(href);
      }
      // Inspect non-navigation links and adorn them if external
     var links = window.document.querySelectorAll(&#39;a[href]:not(.nav-link):not(.navbar-brand):not(.toc-action):not(.sidebar-link):not(.sidebar-item-toggle):not(.pagination-link):not(.no-external):not([aria-hidden]):not(.dropdown-item):not(.quarto-navigation-tool):not(.about-link)&#39;);
      for (var i=0; i&lt;links.length; i++) {
        const link = links[i];
        if (!isInternal(link.href)) {
          // undo the damage that might have been done by quarto-nav.js in the case of
          // links that we want to consider external
          if (link.dataset.originalHref !== undefined) {
            link.href = link.dataset.originalHref;
          }
        }
      }
    function tippyHover(el, contentFn, onTriggerFn, onUntriggerFn) {
      const config = {
        allowHTML: true,
        maxWidth: 500,
        delay: 100,
        arrow: false,
        appendTo: function(el) {
            return el.parentElement;
        },
        interactive: true,
        interactiveBorder: 10,
        theme: &#39;quarto&#39;,
        placement: &#39;bottom-start&#39;,
      };
      if (contentFn) {
        config.content = contentFn;
      }
      if (onTriggerFn) {
        config.onTrigger = onTriggerFn;
      }
      if (onUntriggerFn) {
        config.onUntrigger = onUntriggerFn;
      }
      window.tippy(el, config); 
    }
    const noterefs = window.document.querySelectorAll(&#39;a[role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;]&#39;);
    for (var i=0; i&lt;noterefs.length; i++) {
      const ref = noterefs[i];
      tippyHover(ref, function() {
        // use id or data attribute instead here
        let href = ref.getAttribute(&#39;data-footnote-href&#39;) || ref.getAttribute(&#39;href&#39;);
        try { href = new URL(href).hash; } catch {}
        const id = href.replace(/^#\/?/, &#34;&#34;);
        const note = window.document.getElementById(id);
        if (note) {
          return note.innerHTML;
        } else {
          return &#34;&#34;;
        }
      });
    }
    const xrefs = window.document.querySelectorAll(&#39;a.quarto-xref&#39;);
    const processXRef = (id, note) =&gt; {
      // Strip column container classes
      const stripColumnClz = (el) =&gt; {
        el.classList.remove(&#34;page-full&#34;, &#34;page-columns&#34;);
        if (el.children) {
          for (const child of el.children) {
            stripColumnClz(child);
          }
        }
      }
      stripColumnClz(note)
      if (id === null || id.startsWith(&#39;sec-&#39;)) {
        // Special case sections, only their first couple elements
        const container = document.createElement(&#34;div&#34;);
        if (note.children &amp;&amp; note.children.length &gt; 2) {
          container.appendChild(note.children[0].cloneNode(true));
          for (let i = 1; i &lt; note.children.length; i++) {
            const child = note.children[i];
            if (child.tagName === &#34;P&#34; &amp;&amp; child.innerText === &#34;&#34;) {
              continue;
            } else {
              container.appendChild(child.cloneNode(true));
              break;
            }
          }
          if (window.Quarto?.typesetMath) {
            window.Quarto.typesetMath(container);
          }
          return container.innerHTML
        } else {
          if (window.Quarto?.typesetMath) {
            window.Quarto.typesetMath(note);
          }
          return note.innerHTML;
        }
      } else {
        // Remove any anchor links if they are present
        const anchorLink = note.querySelector(&#39;a.anchorjs-link&#39;);
        if (anchorLink) {
          anchorLink.remove();
        }
        if (window.Quarto?.typesetMath) {
          window.Quarto.typesetMath(note);
        }
        if (note.classList.contains(&#34;callout&#34;)) {
          return note.outerHTML;
        } else {
          return note.innerHTML;
        }
      }
    }
    for (var i=0; i&lt;xrefs.length; i++) {
      const xref = xrefs[i];
      tippyHover(xref, undefined, function(instance) {
        instance.disable();
        let url = xref.getAttribute(&#39;href&#39;);
        let hash = undefined; 
        if (url.startsWith(&#39;#&#39;)) {
          hash = url;
        } else {
          try { hash = new URL(url).hash; } catch {}
        }
        if (hash) {
          const id = hash.replace(/^#\/?/, &#34;&#34;);
          const note = window.document.getElementById(id);
          if (note !== null) {
            try {
              const html = processXRef(id, note.cloneNode(true));
              instance.setContent(html);
            } finally {
              instance.enable();
              instance.show();
            }
          } else {
            // See if we can fetch this
            fetch(url.split(&#39;#&#39;)[0])
            .then(res =&gt; res.text())
            .then(html =&gt; {
              const parser = new DOMParser();
              const htmlDoc = parser.parseFromString(html, &#34;text/html&#34;);
              const note = htmlDoc.getElementById(id);
              if (note !== null) {
                const html = processXRef(id, note);
                instance.setContent(html);
              } 
            }).finally(() =&gt; {
              instance.enable();
              instance.show();
            });
          }
        } else {
          // See if we can fetch a full url (with no hash to target)
          // This is a special case and we should probably do some content thinning / targeting
          fetch(url)
          .then(res =&gt; res.text())
          .then(html =&gt; {
            const parser = new DOMParser();
            const htmlDoc = parser.parseFromString(html, &#34;text/html&#34;);
            const note = htmlDoc.querySelector(&#39;main.content&#39;);
            if (note !== null) {
              // This should only happen for chapter cross references
              // (since there is no id in the URL)
              // remove the first header
              if (note.children.length &gt; 0 &amp;&amp; note.children[0].tagName === &#34;HEADER&#34;) {
                note.children[0].remove();
              }
              const html = processXRef(null, note);
              instance.setContent(html);
            } 
          }).finally(() =&gt; {
            instance.enable();
            instance.show();
          });
        }
      }, function(instance) {
      });
    }
        let selectedAnnoteEl;
        const selectorForAnnotation = ( cell, annotation) =&gt; {
          let cellAttr = &#39;data-code-cell=&#34;&#39; + cell + &#39;&#34;&#39;;
          let lineAttr = &#39;data-code-annotation=&#34;&#39; +  annotation + &#39;&#34;&#39;;
          const selector = &#39;span[&#39; + cellAttr + &#39;][&#39; + lineAttr + &#39;]&#39;;
          return selector;
        }
        const selectCodeLines = (annoteEl) =&gt; {
          const doc = window.document;
          const targetCell = annoteEl.getAttribute(&#34;data-target-cell&#34;);
          const targetAnnotation = annoteEl.getAttribute(&#34;data-target-annotation&#34;);
          const annoteSpan = window.document.querySelector(selectorForAnnotation(targetCell, targetAnnotation));
          const lines = annoteSpan.getAttribute(&#34;data-code-lines&#34;).split(&#34;,&#34;);
          const lineIds = lines.map((line) =&gt; {
            return targetCell + &#34;-&#34; + line;
          })
          let top = null;
          let height = null;
          let parent = null;
          if (lineIds.length &gt; 0) {
              //compute the position of the single el (top and bottom and make a div)
              const el = window.document.getElementById(lineIds[0]);
              top = el.offsetTop;
              height = el.offsetHeight;
              parent = el.parentElement.parentElement;
            if (lineIds.length &gt; 1) {
              const lastEl = window.document.getElementById(lineIds[lineIds.length - 1]);
              const bottom = lastEl.offsetTop + lastEl.offsetHeight;
              height = bottom - top;
            }
            if (top !== null &amp;&amp; height !== null &amp;&amp; parent !== null) {
              // cook up a div (if necessary) and position it 
              let div = window.document.getElementById(&#34;code-annotation-line-highlight&#34;);
              if (div === null) {
                div = window.document.createElement(&#34;div&#34;);
                div.setAttribute(&#34;id&#34;, &#34;code-annotation-line-highlight&#34;);
                div.style.position = &#39;absolute&#39;;
                parent.appendChild(div);
              }
              div.style.top = top - 2 + &#34;px&#34;;
              div.style.height = height + 4 + &#34;px&#34;;
              div.style.left = 0;
              let gutterDiv = window.document.getElementById(&#34;code-annotation-line-highlight-gutter&#34;);
              if (gutterDiv === null) {
                gutterDiv = window.document.createElement(&#34;div&#34;);
                gutterDiv.setAttribute(&#34;id&#34;, &#34;code-annotation-line-highlight-gutter&#34;);
                gutterDiv.style.position = &#39;absolute&#39;;
                const codeCell = window.document.getElementById(targetCell);
                const gutter = codeCell.querySelector(&#39;.code-annotation-gutter&#39;);
                gutter.appendChild(gutterDiv);
              }
              gutterDiv.style.top = top - 2 + &#34;px&#34;;
              gutterDiv.style.height = height + 4 + &#34;px&#34;;
            }
            selectedAnnoteEl = annoteEl;
          }
        };
        const unselectCodeLines = () =&gt; {
          const elementsIds = [&#34;code-annotation-line-highlight&#34;, &#34;code-annotation-line-highlight-gutter&#34;];
          elementsIds.forEach((elId) =&gt; {
            const div = window.document.getElementById(elId);
            if (div) {
              div.remove();
            }
          });
          selectedAnnoteEl = undefined;
        };
          // Handle positioning of the toggle
      window.addEventListener(
        &#34;resize&#34;,
        throttle(() =&gt; {
          elRect = undefined;
          if (selectedAnnoteEl) {
            selectCodeLines(selectedAnnoteEl);
          }
        }, 10)
      );
      function throttle(fn, ms) {
      let throttle = false;
      let timer;
        return (...args) =&gt; {
          if(!throttle) { // first call gets through
              fn.apply(this, args);
              throttle = true;
          } else { // all the others get throttled
              if(timer) clearTimeout(timer); // cancel #2
              timer = setTimeout(() =&gt; {
                fn.apply(this, args);
                timer = throttle = false;
              }, ms);
          }
        };
      }
        // Attach click handler to the DT
        const annoteDls = window.document.querySelectorAll(&#39;dt[data-target-cell]&#39;);
        for (const annoteDlNode of annoteDls) {
          annoteDlNode.addEventListener(&#39;click&#39;, (event) =&gt; {
            const clickedEl = event.target;
            if (clickedEl !== selectedAnnoteEl) {
              unselectCodeLines();
              const activeEl = window.document.querySelector(&#39;dt[data-target-cell].code-annotation-active&#39;);
              if (activeEl) {
                activeEl.classList.remove(&#39;code-annotation-active&#39;);
              }
              selectCodeLines(clickedEl);
              clickedEl.classList.add(&#39;code-annotation-active&#39;);
            } else {
              // Unselect the line
              unselectCodeLines();
              clickedEl.classList.remove(&#39;code-annotation-active&#39;);
            }
          });
        }
    const findCites = (el) =&gt; {
      const parentEl = el.parentElement;
      if (parentEl) {
        const cites = parentEl.dataset.cites;
        if (cites) {
          return {
            el,
            cites: cites.split(&#39; &#39;)
          };
        } else {
          return findCites(el.parentElement)
        }
      } else {
        return undefined;
      }
    };
    var bibliorefs = window.document.querySelectorAll(&#39;a[role=&#34;doc-biblioref&#34;]&#39;);
    for (var i=0; i&lt;bibliorefs.length; i++) {
      const ref = bibliorefs[i];
      const citeInfo = findCites(ref);
      if (citeInfo) {
        tippyHover(citeInfo.el, function() {
          var popup = window.document.createElement(&#39;div&#39;);
          citeInfo.cites.forEach(function(cite) {
            var citeDiv = window.document.createElement(&#39;div&#39;);
            citeDiv.classList.add(&#39;hanging-indent&#39;);
            citeDiv.classList.add(&#39;csl-entry&#39;);
            var biblioDiv = window.document.getElementById(&#39;ref-&#39; + cite);
            if (biblioDiv) {
              citeDiv.innerHTML = biblioDiv.innerHTML;
            }
            popup.appendChild(citeDiv);
          });
          return popup.innerHTML;
        });
      }
    }
  });
  &lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt; &lt;!-- /content --&gt;




&lt;/body&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/talk/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;us-federal-agency-policymaking&#34;&gt;U.S. Federal Agency Policymaking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/judgelord/regulationsdotgov-DATA&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;github.com/judgelord/regulationsdotgov-DATA&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Files and metadata for all documents (proposed rules, rules, public comments) on regulations.gov collected with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/judgelord/regulationsdotgov&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;regulationsdotgov&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; R package&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/judgelord/rulemaking&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;github.com/judgelord/rulemaking&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/judgelord/rulemaking?tab=readme-ov-file#unified-agenda-of-regulatory-and-deregulatory-actions&#34;&gt;Unified Agenda of Regulatory and Deregulatory Actions&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;for a SQL version of the Unified Agenda, bulk Federal Register metadata, and other data sources discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/research/regdata/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Data and Methods Analyzing Special Interests Influence in Rulemaking,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; see &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/libgober/regdata&#34;&gt;this collaborative repository&lt;/a&gt; ]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/judgelord/rulemaking?tab=readme-ov-file#office-of-information-and-regulatory-affairs-oria-reports&#34;&gt;Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (ORIA) Reports&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This repository also includes the older versions of SQL and Rdata files for regulations.gov metadata through 2020 that I used for my dissertation. The new architecture in &lt;code&gt;regulationsdotgov-DATA&lt;/code&gt; is more complete and easier to work with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;requests-from-members-of-congress-to-us-federal-agencies&#34;&gt;Requests from Members of Congress to U.S. Federal Agencies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.7910/DVN/LWOCWO&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Harvard Dataverse Replication Data&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional documentation for the replication data &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/judgelord/corr&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates from this ongoing project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/correspondence/&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;university-of-michgian&#34;&gt;University of Michgian&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/PP475-750/&#34;&gt;PubPol 475/750: Protest, Social Movements, Art, and Policy Change&lt;/a&gt; (Undergraduate/Graduate, 2026)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/PP510&#34;&gt;PubPol 510: The Politics of Public Policy - Energy&lt;/a&gt; (Graduate, 2024, 2025)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/PP495&#34;&gt;PubPol 495: Climate Change and Democracy&lt;/a&gt; (Undergraduate, 2024, 2025)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/PP475/&#34;&gt;PubPol 475: Politics for the Anthropocene&lt;/a&gt; (Undergraduate, 2024, 2025)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/PP510&#34;&gt;PubPol 510: The Politics of Public Policy - Water&lt;/a&gt; (Graduate, 2023)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;university-of-wisconsin-madison&#34;&gt;University of Wisconsin-Madison&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/PS272/syllabus-PS272-2020.html&#34;&gt;PS 272: Public Policy&lt;/a&gt; (Undergraduate, 2019, 2020)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://judgelord.github.io/PS811/&#34;&gt;PS 811: Statistical Computing for Political Science&lt;/a&gt;  (Graduate, 2019)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching Assistant/Grader&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public Policy (Undergraduate, 2016, 2017, 2018)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policing in the United States (Undergraduate, 2015)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;yale-university&#34;&gt;Yale University&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teaching Fellow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Politics and Practice of Environmental Policy (Graduate, 2012)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Economics of Ecosystems and Biodiversity (Graduate, 2011)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Templates</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/templates/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
