<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steven Rashin | </title>
    <link>https://judgelord.github.io/authors/steven-rashin/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://judgelord.github.io/authors/steven-rashin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Steven Rashin</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://judgelord.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Steven Rashin</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/authors/steven-rashin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data and Methods for Analyzing Special Interest Influence in Rulemaking</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/regdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/regdata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The US government creates astonishingly complete records of policy creation in executive agencies. In this article, we describe the major kinds of data that have proven useful to scholars studying interest group behavior and influence in bureaucratic politics, how to obtain them, and challenges that we as users have encountered in working with these data. We discuss established databases such as regulations.gov, which contains comments on draft agency rules, and newer sources of data, such as ex-parte meeting logs, which describe the interest groups and individual lobbyists that bureaucrats are meeting face-to-face about proposed policies. One challenge is that much of these data are not machine-readable. We argue that scholars should invest in several projects to make these datasets machine-readable and to link them to each other as well as to other databases.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inequality in Administrative Democracy</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/finreg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/finreg/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research on inequality overlooks administrative policymaking, where most U.S. law is currently made, under pressure from vast flows of money, lobbying, and political mobilization. Analyzing a new database of over 260,000 comments on agency rules implementing the Dodd-Frank Act, we identify the lobbying activities of over 6,000 organizations. Leveraging measures of organizations’ wealth, participation in administrative politics, sophistication, and lobbying success, we provide the first large-scale assessment of wealth-based inequality in agency rulemaking. We find that wealthier organizations are more likely to participate in rulemaking and enjoy more success in shifting the content of federal agency rules. These patterns are not explained by membership differentials. More profit-driven organizations are also more likely to participate and enjoy more success in shifting the content of federal agency rules. Wealthier organizations’ ability to marshal legal and technical expertise appears to be a key mechanism by which wealth leads to lobbying success.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
