<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kenneth Mayer | </title>
    <link>https://judgelord.github.io/authors/kenneth-mayer/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://judgelord.github.io/authors/kenneth-mayer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Kenneth Mayer</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://judgelord.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Kenneth Mayer</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/authors/kenneth-mayer/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Literature with Networks: An Application to Redistricting</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/netlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/netlit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Understanding the gaps and connections across existing theories and findings is a perennial challenge in
scientific research. Systematically reviewing scholarship is especially challenging for researchers who may
lack domain expertise, including junior scholars or those exploring new substantive territory. Conversely,
senior scholars may rely on long-standing assumptions and social networks that exclude new research. In
both cases, ad hoc literature reviews hinder accumulation of knowledge. Scholars are rarely systematic in
selecting relevant prior work or then identifying patterns across their sample. To encourage systematic, replicable, and transparent methods for assessing literature, we propose an accessible network-based framework
for reviewing scholarship. In our method, we consider a literature as a network of recurring concepts (nodes)
and theorized relationships among them (edges). Network statistics and visualization allow researchers
to see patterns and offer reproducible characterizations of assertions about the major themes in existing
literature. Critically, our approach is systematic and powerful but also low cost; it requires researchers
to enter relationships they observe in prior studies into a simple spreadsheet—a task accessible to new
and experienced researchers alike. Our open-source R package enables researchers to leverage powerful
network analysis while minimizing software-specific knowledge. We demonstrate this approach by reviewing
redistricting literature&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
