<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eleanor Neff Powell | </title>
    <link>https://judgelord.github.io/authors/eleanor-neff-powell/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://judgelord.github.io/authors/eleanor-neff-powell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Eleanor Neff Powell</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://judgelord.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Eleanor Neff Powell</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/authors/eleanor-neff-powell/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Shifting Priorities and Capacity on Policy Work and Constituency Service</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/correspondence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/correspondence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When elected officials gain power, do they use it to provide more constituent service or affect policy? The answer informs debates over how legislator capacity, term limits, and institutional positions affect legislator behavior.  We distinguish two countervailing effects of increased institutional power: shifting priorities and increased capacity.  To assess how institutional power shapes behavior, we assemble a massive new database of 611,239 legislator requests to a near census of federal departments, agencies, and sub-agencies between 2007 and 2020. We find that legislators prioritize policy work as they gain institutional power (e.g., become a committee chair) but simultaneously maintain their levels of constituency service. Moreover, when a new legislator replaces an experienced legislator, the district receives less constituency service &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; less policy work. Rather than long-serving and powerful elected officials diverting attention from constituents, their increased capacity enables them to maintain levels of constituency service, even as they prioritize policy work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legislator Advocacy on Behalf of Constituents and Corporate Donors</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/ferc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/ferc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We use letters that legislators write to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to study congressional attempts to influence bureaucratic decisions. Analyzing thousands of letters that legislators sent to the agency over nearly two decades, we find that these letters are filled with specific references to companies that legislators seek to assist or about which the legislator’s constituents have complaints. We explore which legislators seek to influence the agency, on whose behalf legislators advocate, and the kinds of outcomes they attempt to influence. We find that most individual constituent letters oppose proposed energy projects, but most non-constituent letters advocate in favor of named businesses. Finally, we assess whether legislators’ advocacy behavior is related to the campaign contributions they receive from the energy industry. We find that Republicans and those who receive money from the energy sector write to advocate for energy companies, but not their constituents, while Democrats write comparatively more letters in opposition to energy companies. Campaign contributions are much stronger predictors of pro-business advocacy than other kinds of attention to energy issues, such as energy-related constituency service or advocacy against energy projects. For example, a legislator who receives $200,000 from the energy sector is twice as likely to write advocating on behalf of an energy company than a legislator who received no energy-sector money but no more likely to write on behalf of their constituents or in opposition to an energy project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Gets Constituent Service?</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/correp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/correp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words and Deeds: Do Legislators&#39; Public Messages Reflect Their Behind-the-Scenes Work with Federal Agencies?</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/corinbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/corinbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do legislators’ words match their deeds?
We contribute to the promise-keeping literature by introducing “attention consistency” as a measure of representation, theorizing conditions that should produce more consistency between public messaging and behavior in office, and testing whether legislators’ public attention to federal agencies in constituent newsletters corresponds to their private engagement with those agencies.
We find strong evidence of attention consistency in cross-sectional and within-member analyses in the volume of legislators&amp;rsquo; attention.
Robustness checks evaluating the distribution of legislator attention yield similar results.
Legislators who publicly emphasize an agency engage more with that agency behind the scenes.
We find no evidence that ideological distance from an agency conditions the consistency of legislators&amp;rsquo; public and private attention to it.
Similarly, while members of relevant oversight committees make more requests of agencies they oversee, we find no evidence that oversight membership conditions the consistency of legislators&amp;rsquo; public and private attention to it.
Our analyses show that legislators&amp;rsquo; interests, as expressed in their attention to that agency in their newsletters, matter as much as institutional roles in shaping legislators&amp;rsquo; behind-the-scenes interactions with federal agencies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
