<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eleanor Neff Powell | </title>
    <link>https://judgelord.github.io/authors/eleanor-neff-powell/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://judgelord.github.io/authors/eleanor-neff-powell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Eleanor Neff Powell</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>https://judgelord.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Eleanor Neff Powell</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/authors/eleanor-neff-powell/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legislator Advocacy on Behalf of Constituents and Corporate Donors</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/ferc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/ferc/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effects of Shifting Priorities and Capacity on Policy Work and Constituency Service</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/correspondence/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/correspondence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When elected officials gain power, do they use it to provide more constituent service or to affect broad public policies? Answering this question informs debates over
how legislator capacity, term limits, and institutional power affect political representation. We distinguish two countervailing effects of increased institutional power. First,
as elected officials gain power, they allocate relatively more effort to policy over constituency service. Second, institutional power provides additional resources and therefore increases their overall capacity. To assess the extent to which these countervailing
effects of institutional power affect behavior, we assemble a massive new database of
487,890 Congressional requests to federal agencies between 2007 and 2018 obtained
through 429 FOIA requests, a near census of departments, agencies, and sub-agencies.
We find that most legislator contacts with the bureaucracy are constituency service,
regardless of institutional position and tenure. Leveraging variation within legislatoragency pairs, we show that legislators prioritize policy work as they gain power and
experience, but increasing overall capacity enables them to maintain levels of constituency service. Consistent with our theory that service depends on capacity, we
show that new legislators do less policy work and constituency service than their more
senior colleagues. In a series of robustness checks, we show that our findings are not
the result of exogenous variation in constituent demand. Rather than long-serving and
powerful elected officials diverting attention from their district, their increased capacity
enables them to maintain levels of constituency service, even as they prioritize policy
work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Gets Constituent Service?</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/correp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/correp/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
