<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Templates | </title>
    <link>/templates/</link>
      <atom:link href="/templates/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Templates</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Templates</title>
      <link>/templates/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/templates/rmd-templates/abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/templates/rmd-templates/abstract/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political Information in Bureaucratic Policymaking&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Devin Judge-Lord&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This dissertation examines the effects of public pressure campaigns on agency rulemaking, a technocratic policy process where “public participation” is usually limited to sophisticated lobbying but occasionally includes millions of people mobilized by public pressure campaigns. Public comment periods on proposed policies purport to provide democratic accountability. Yet theories of bureaucratic policymaking largely ignore the occasional bursts of civic engagement that generate the vast majority of public comments on proposed rules. To fill this gap, I build and test theories about the role of public pressure in policymaking. I collect and analyze millions of public comments to develop the first systematic measures of civic engagement and influence in bureaucratic policymaking. Four substantive chapters address (1) how and why advocacy groups mobilize ordinary people to engage in rulemaking; (2) how public pressure draws the attention of elected officials; (3) how public pressure impacts policy outcomes; and (4) how the environmental justice movement has used opportunities to participate in rulemaking to affect policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first chapter (&lt;a href=&#34;judgelord.github.io/research/whymail/&#34;&gt;Why Do Agencies (Sometimes) Get So Much Mail?&lt;/a&gt;), addresses who participates in public pressure campaigns and why. Are public pressure campaigns, like other lobbying tactics, primarily used by well-resourced groups to create an impression of public support? Or are they better understood as conflict expansion tactics used by less-resourced groups? To answer these questions, I collect and analyze millions of public comments on draft agency rules. Using text analysis methods underlying plagiarism detection, I match individual public comments to pressure-group campaigns. I find that most public comments are mobilized by a few public interest organizations. Over 80% of the 48 million comments on proposed rules posted to regulations.gov were mobilized by just 100 organizations, 87 of which lobby in coalitions with each other. Contrary to other forms of lobbying, I find that mass comment campaigns are almost always a conflict expansion tactic, rather than well-resourced groups creating an impression of public support. Contrary to other forms of political participation, I find no evidence of negativity bias in public comments. Indeed, from 2005 to 2017, most comments supported proposed rules. This is because public comments tend to support Democratic policies and oppose Republican policies, reflecting the asymmetry in mobilizing groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second substantive chapter examines the effect of public pressure campaigns on congressional oversight. I assess whether legislators are more likely to engage in rulemaking when advocacy groups mobilize public pressure. This involves collecting and coding thousands of comments from Members of Congress on proposed rules with and without public pressure campaigns. These data also allow me to assess congressional oversight as a mediator in policy influence, i.e., the extent to which public pressure campaigns affect agency decisionmakers directly or indirectly through their effects on elected officials’ oversight behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a third chapter, I use a mix of hand-coding and computational text analysis methods to assess whether public pressure campaigns increase lobbying success in agency rulemaking. To measure lobbying success, I develop computational methods to identify lobbying coalitions and estimate lobbying success for all rules posted for comment on regulations.gov. These methods are validated against a random sample of 100 rules with a mass-comment campaign and 100 rules without a mass comment campaign that I hand-code for whether each coalition got the policy outcome they sought. I then assess potential mechanisms by which mass public engagement may affect policy. Each mechanism involves a distinct type of information revealed to decisionmakers.
&lt;!--Of primary interest is the extent to which public pressure campaigns affect agency decisionmakers directly or indirectly through their effects on elected officials&#39; oversight behaviors. I test this by assessing congressional oversight as a causal mediator using a subset of rules where I collect and code correspondence from Member of Congress to agencies about proposed agency rules.--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&#34;judgelord.github.io/research/ej/&#34;&gt;final chapter&lt;/a&gt; focuses on the impact of the environmental justice movement in agency rulemaking. I examine the discursive effects of environmental justice claims both qualitatively and quantitatively. I write about the role of Native activists and environmental groups in shaping federal environmental regulations. Looking across over 20,000 draft regulations that failed to address environmental justice issues, I find that agencies are more likely to add language addressing environmental justice in their final rules when public comments raise environmental justice concerns. However, I have yet to find evidence that mass comment campaigns make this more likely.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/templates/rmd-templates/djl-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/templates/rmd-templates/djl-letter/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;script src=&#34;/rmarkdown-libs/header-attrs/header-attrs.js&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;To whom it may concern:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I write to apply for the Kendall Fellowship in Understanding Scientist Activism and Movement Building. As a fourth-year doctoral candidate, the Fellowship would support the final year of my Ph.D. research and a year of post-doctoral research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;research-concept&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Research concept&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political scientists have long studied how social movements influence elected officials, but we have much to learn about how activists and public pressure may influence bureaucratic policymaking and the role that tactics like mass-comment campaigns play in movement-building. My dissertation examines how advocacy organizations mobilize supporters to amplify more technical lobbying efforts. I focus on agency rulemaking, where most U.S. law is now made, and where organizations like UCS often mobilize thousands of people to engage. To the extent that this tactic aims to influence policy, it presumes that policymakers are more likely to respond to demands amplified by mass mobilization campaigns. While plausible that mass engagement may affect agency decisions both directly, by realizing latent public demands, and indirectly, by influencing elected officials whose opinions matter to agency policymakers, these hypotheses remain untested. We know very little about the conditions under which mass mobilization aimed at bureaucratic policymaking succeeds and the mechanisms by which it may affect policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My research begins to fill this gap. I develop systematic measures of public engagement in rulemaking over time using text reuse and Bayesian classifiers to link millions of public comments to the advocacy efforts they support.
I then use my new measures of public engagement to assess the effects of mobilization on policy by linking changes in policy texts and the policymaking process to the demands of each coalition. For example, in preliminary work for a chapter on the influence of environmental justice (EJ) activists in rulemaking, I compare the preambles of draft and final rules and analyze the comments submitted on each rule. I identify 21,544 draft agency rules that plausibly affect EJ issues but do not mention “environmental justice.’’ In comments submitted on 1,496 of these draft rules, commenters raised “environmental justice” as a concern. When they did, agencies were more likely to add EJ language when publishing the final rule. This suggests that advocacy efforts may indeed influence rulemaking. While I have yet to find an effect for the volume of public comments, I am developing more sophisticated methods to better test the hypothesis that agencies are more likely to respond to demands amplified by mass mobilization campaigns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second part of my dissertation explores how and when Members of Congress are mobilized to engage in agency decisions. Here, I collaborate with Eleanor Powell and Justin Grimmer, leading scholars on legislator behavior. Through hundreds of Freedom of Information Act requests, we created a new dataset of hundreds of thousands of letters, emails, and phone calls from legislators to bureaucrats. I use this dataset to identify how advocacy campaigns mobilize or “scare off’” legislator engagement in agency decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Kendall Fellowship would also allow me to advance a third key part of this research agenda: assessing how different &lt;em&gt;tactics&lt;/em&gt; mobilize individuals and elected officials and ultimately affect policy. Specifically, I hope to collaborate with organizations like UCS in two ways. First, I hope to integrate data on responses to public engagement campaigns, such as click-through rates for action alerts, data on those engaged, and any personalized text they added. I see these as key to measuring the intensity of public demands and the potential for movements to spread. Second, I hope to help design small randomly-assigned variations in future mobilization efforts—for example, messaging with and without an EJ frame—and use the methods I developed in my dissertation to track legislator and agency responses. Eventually, I hope to collect sufficient experimental evidence to causally identify effects of public engagement on policy, but the results of even a few experimental manipulations may reveal mechanisms of influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;experience&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Experience&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hold master’s degrees in Environmental Science and Political Science and have significant research and policy experience beyond academia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2009 to 2011, I developed and led a collaborative initiative for Willamette Partnership, a watershed-based nonprofit. This involved convening groups of experts, advocates, and policymakers to draft agency guidance and state law around Clean Water Act and Endangered Species Act regulations and Farm Bill Conservation Title criteria. I also helped develop strategic plans for Willamette Partnership, and for the Oregon Sierra Club in my role as Vice Chair of the Columbia Chapter, and I would be excited to help plan the Center for Science and Democracy’s future efforts to empower the scientific community and our supporters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 2013 to 2015, I worked for the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations, analyzing changes in forestry laws. This research emerged from my M.E.Sc. work, where I wrote a book chapter tracing the effects of U.S. NGOs and indigenous activists on forestry laws and a journal article on the evolution of initiatives like the Forest Stewardship Council.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2015, I have been working on my Ph.D. at the University of Wisconsin where I currently teach a class on statistical computing for Ph.D. students. I also hold positions in the Association for Environmental Studies and Sciences and the American Political Science Association’s Science, Technology, and Environmental Politics section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an organization that mobilizes supporters to amplify science and realize latent public demands, UCS, and the Center for Science and Democracy offer an ideal environment to advance my research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your consideration,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devin Judge-Lord&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
