<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>6 | </title>
    <link>https://judgelord.github.io/publication_types/6/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://judgelord.github.io/publication_types/6/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>6</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://judgelord.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>6</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/publication_types/6/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Legislator Advocacy on Behalf of Constituents and Corporate Donors</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/ferc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 1969 19:33:43 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/ferc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We use letters that legislators write to the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to study congressional attempts to influence bureaucratic decisions. Analyzing thousands of letters that legislators sent to the agency over nearly two decades, we find that these letters are filled with specific references to companies that legislators seek to assist or about which the legislator’s constituents have complaints. We explore which legislators seek to influence the agency, on whose behalf legislators advocate, and the kinds of outcomes they attempt to influence. We find that most individual constituent letters oppose proposed energy projects, but most non-constituent letters advocate in favor of named businesses. Finally, we assess whether legislators’ advocacy behavior is related to the campaign contributions they receive from the energy industry. We find that Republicans and those who receive money from the energy sector write to advocate for energy companies, but not their constituents, while Democrats write comparatively more letters in opposition to energy companies. Campaign contributions are much stronger predictors of pro-business advocacy than other kinds of attention to energy issues, such as energy-related constituency service or advocacy against energy projects. For example, a legislator who receives $200,000 from the energy sector is twice as likely to write advocating on behalf of an energy company than a legislator who received no energy-sector money but no more likely to write on behalf of their constituents or in opposition to an energy project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Non-domestic Sources of Canadian Boreal Forest Policy</title>
      <link>https://judgelord.github.io/research/boreal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://judgelord.github.io/research/boreal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Environmental groups’ interest in, and attention to, Canadian boreal forest protection and management is a relatively new phenomenon vis-à-vis the longstanding focus on Canadian temperate forests. Nevertheless, policy development affecting the Canadian boreal forest has, in the past decade, been punctuated towards a new equilibrium in which both protection and forest management policies have increased dramatically. What explains this punctuation? This chapter addresses this question by exploring the role of non-domestic forces in shaping Canadian boreal forest policies. We examine the International Boreal Conservation Campaign (IBCC) initiated by the Philadelphia-based Pew Charitable Trusts and the Canadian Boreal Forest Agreement, using Bernstein and Cashore’s pathways framework (2002, updated 2012), which identifes four distinct pathways through which non-domestic factors can infuence domestic policy change. Through inductive historical-process tracing, we develop two related arguments. First, non-domestic factors do not explain policy change itself, which arguably would have occurred even in the absence of international pressures, but they help explain both the pace and scale of change. In other words, the changes would have likely taken longer and been of lesser scale if not for the infuence of non-domestic factors in general and the IBCC in particular. Second, we argue that while much attention has focused on the markets pathway, a signifcant amount of effort along the direct-access pathway helps account for much of the noted policy changes. As a result, we call for more study of direct access of international groups in domestic policy and interaction among the pathways. We conclude by reviewing the implications of these fndings both for theories of internationalisation and policy change as well as implications for environmental and business strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
